翻译
17 石佛 monica-卡
OckRazor Neon Oliver 渣打毛线
校对
monica-卡 17 OckRazor 佳东 清野 natas RN
时间轴
框 17 monica-卡 natas RN
谢谢大家 你们好
Thank you, everybody! Hello.
谢谢
Thank you.
谢谢你们的热情
Thank you so much!
非常感谢
Thank you, everybody. Thank you so much.
这里是The Grand Tour
This is The Grand Tour,
这周 我们回家了
and this week... we've come home!
我们回来啦 我们又回到英国了
We're back! We're back in Britain.
准确地说 我们现在在约克郡
We're actually in Yorkshire, which is...
没错
There you go.
也正是我们仨长大的地方
Which is where all three of us grew up.
-确切的讲  -惠特比
- Specifically-- Yeah, specifically... Whitby!
确切的讲 我们正在惠特比的渔港 后面就是
We're in the fishing port of Whitby. There it is.
当然 惠特比因为其不可思议的炸鱼薯条
Now, Whitby, of course, is famous all around the world
而闻名世界
for its unbelievable fish and chips.
和 scraps
- With scraps.
scraps 碎渣 和后面bits同义
什么
You what?
炸鱼薯条和 scraps 每次里面都有 scraps
Fish and chips with scraps. You get scraps.
就是那些黏在锅底的面糊
Little bits of batter that stay in the bottom of the fryer.
-对啊 scraps -不对 那叫 bits
-Yeah, scraps. -No, they're bits.
-炸鱼薯片和bits -不 scraps
-Fish and chips with bits. -No, it's scraps.
就是 bits
It is bits! Bits!
这样 觉得应该叫 bits 的举手
Right, hands up for bits.
-大错特错  -支持 scraps 的举手
- Wrong! - Scraps?
-看 就叫 scraps -别和我争
-See, it's scraps. -Don't argue with me.
因为我出生在约克郡
Because I was born in Yorkshire.
从17世纪起 我家族里的每一个人都住在这里
Every single one of my family back to the 17th century's from Yorkshire.
我是世界上血统最纯正的约克郡人
I'm the most Yorkshire person in the world.
是吗 有意思了
You know, it's funny,
因为根本看不出来 完全没法分辨
cos you can't tell. You really wouldn't know.
约克郡人是出名的心直口快
- Yorkshire people are famous for speaking their mind.
但你...我们就...
And when you... We...
我们永远不知道你在想什么 这简直
We never know what you're thinking. It's just...
猜猜我现在在想什么
What am I thinking now?
你在想 自己真是才华横溢
You're thinking you're brilliant
而我就是个烦人的小矮子
and I'm an irritating little short-arse.
-你怎么猜到的  -怎么说
-How did you know? -Yeah, it's just...
-这简直不可思议  -是的 我会读心术 同志
-It's incredible! -Yeah, I'm psychic, mate.
约克郡的板球也很出名 这没意思
Other things Yorkshire's cricket. That's not interesting.
还有个电视剧 最后的夏日美酒
Ooh, and then there was a TV show called Last Of The Summer Wine,
讲述了三个衣着丑陋的老男人的故事
which was about three very badly dressed old men
他们总是碰壁
who fell over,
总能办砸每件事
and everything they ever did went wrong.
-太烂了  -没法看
- It was rubbish. - Yeah, terrible.
完全不知道他们怎么火的
I don't know why that took off.
约克郡的造车业
Erm... Carmaking?
这么说吧
Well, let's put it this way.
不能说这是英岛的底特律
It's not exactly the Detroit of the British Isles.
确实不能
No, it's not.
但本周这却有许多和车有关的活动
But there is a lot of motoring-related stuff here this week,
因为我们来了
because we're in town.
所以 让我们开始今天的节目吧
So, let's get on with the show.
开始吧
Yes, let's.
我们得从维多利亚时代说起
We begin in Victorian times,
那时詹姆斯梅还是个年轻老太婆
when James May was a little old lady.
当时 有钱的男士...
You see, back then, gentlemen of means--
也就是穿着花呢西装的有钱人
-Rich people in tweed suits.
没错 穿着花呢西装的有钱人
-Yes, rich people in tweed suits
他们会进行所谓的大壮游
would take what was known as the Grand Tour.
去到法国或意大利
They'd go off to France or Italy,
花几个月学习当地的文化
and they'd spend a few months learning about culture
酒和音乐
and wine and music.
而现在 大家去的是马盖鲁夫
Nowadays, of course, everybody goes to Magaluf
在那学习喝酒 醉吐 然后滥交
and learns about beer and vomit and chlamydia.
世风日下
Yeah.
我们觉得这很可惜
Now, we think this is a real shame,
所以杰瑞米和我去到了意大利
so Jeremy and I went off to Italy
进行了自己现代意义上的大壮游
to do our own modern take on the Grand Tour.
那是一段淋漓尽致启迪人心的旅程
A wonderful, inspirational journey
不仅最后成为了我们节目名字
that not only gave its name to this show,
还成了数千台GT车的名字
but also to 1,000 GT cars:
豪华旅行车
grand tourers.
我们从托斯卡纳山顶城市 锡耶纳 出发
Our start point was the Tuscan hilltop city of Siena.
这是世界上最激动人心的赛马比赛发源地
Home to the most exciting horse race in the world:
派力奥赛马节
the Palio.
看那匹马 太棒了
Look at that! Wow!
这应是一段精彩的
It was the beginning of what would be a very fabulous
文化之旅的开端
and very cultured journey.
我们沿途会游览美丽的佛罗伦萨
We'd visit the magnificent cities of Florence
博洛尼亚和维罗纳
and Bologna and Verona
直到终点
on our way to the finishing point
这其中最宏伟的城市
in the most magnificent city of them all:
威尼斯
Venice.
我们开的车也丝毫不逊色
The cars we'd be driving were fabulous, too.
詹姆斯选择了劳斯莱斯曜影
James had chosen the Rolls-Royce Dawn,
也就是古斯特的双门敞篷版
a new two-door, drop-head version of the Ghost.
我选了DB11
And I'd be in the DB11,
阿斯顿马丁优雅美丽的豪华旅行车系列
the latest in a long line
之中的最新款
of elegant and beautiful Aston Martin grand tourers.
它的后视镜都如此有美感
Even its door mirrors are beautiful.
它的车轮也这么美
Its wheels are beautiful.
这真是...
This is...
这真是我见过最漂亮的车之一
This is one of the most beautiful cars I've ever seen.
可惜是棕色的
Shame it's brown.
-这不是棕色  -怎么不是
-It isn't brown! -Yes, it is.
这是日落橙
It isn't brown! It's Sunset Orange.
这要不是棕色 那我的车就是绿色
It's not brown in the way that my car is green.
这就是棕色
It's brown.
你的车实际就是敞篷版的宝马7系
Your car is a convertible BMW 7 Series.
才不是
No, it isn't.
这底下不就是宝马7系吗
But is it a 7 Series underneath?
-有点共用的底盘件 -所以嘛
-Bits of the floor panel. -There you go.
一辆230多万的敞篷宝马7系
￡265,000 for a convertible 7 Series.
才不是
It isn't!
如果你要在意大利自驾游
If you're going to drive across Italy,
学习当地文化
which we're going to do, taking in some culture...
-怎么  -得开这样的车
-Mm-hm. -...that's what you need.
-开辆棕色的车吗  -这不是棕色
-A brown car? -It isn't brown!
-就是棕色  -我们也别争了
-It's brown! -Look, let's not bicker.
我们出发吧
Actually, on this occasion, let's get on.
我们俩要开车穿越
We are both going to drive across
我认为是咱们最喜欢的国家
what is, I think, our favourite country in the world,
享受文化 美酒
enjoy some culture, enjoy some fine wine,
美食 艺术...
some food, some art, some...
那是谁
What was that?
-那是哈蒙德吗  -不好意思 我迟到了
-Is that Hammond? -Sorry I'm late.
我们不知道你会来
We didn't know you were coming.
我们也不希望你会来
We rather hoped you weren't.
但是我就来了 看看我选的车
Well, I am, and look at the car I've brought.
道奇挑战者SRT地狱猫
Dodge Challenger SRT Hellcat.
707匹马力
707 American horsepower,
扭矩力大到可以拉倒那座老房子
and enough torque to pull that old building down.
别 那老房子可是...
Just... That "old building" is a...
算了 和你讲不清
Oh, well, never mind.
哈蒙德 在托斯卡纳不适合开肌肉车
Hammond, Tuscany, not really the home of the muscle car.
我就是担心你俩会这么无聊严肃
Yeah, you see, I was worried you two were gonna be all boring and serious.
我就是来确保这是段有趣的旅程
And I am here to make sure this trip is fun
别告诉我 最开始的大壮游并不有趣
because don't tell me the original Grand Tour wasn't fun.
那就是18世纪的炮弹飞车
It was like an 18th century Cannonball Run,
炮弹飞车 关于跨美车赛的电影
只是大家打的是传统吗啡 而不是可卡因
only with old-fashioned morphine instead of cocaine.
开这车来 才合适
This is gonna be brilliant.
你车上的广告怎么回事
What's with your advertising?
因为美国人以前做壮游时
Well, because the Americans used to do the Grand Tour,
都会找赞助商承担开销
and they used to get sponsors to help cover the costs,
所以我也给自己找了些赞助
so I've got myself some sponsorship.
波比的... 什么是grit
What, Bobby's... What is a grit?
就是... 大概...
That's a... It's a...
好像是咖啡渣或者土豆泥
a bit left over after coffee or potatoes?
-我没听说过  -如广告所示
-I don't know. -Well, it's there.
牛仔润滑油改装厂
"Rodeo Lube 'N' Tune."
润滑油改装厂 厉害吧
"Lube 'N' Tune." Yep, look at that.
别人一看我这
The things is, people will look at me in that
就知道我在大壮游
and know I am on a Grand Tour.
你们呢 他们会觉得 这两个傻犊子在干什么
You, they'll think, "What are these two old farts doing?"
-说真的...  -你什么都没准备
- Seriously-- - You have made no effort.
连情绪都没酝酿好
You haven't got into the mood for this.
艺术 音乐 文化
Art, music, culture.
-精致  -对
- Refinement. - Yes.
这是你的吗
Is this something to do with you?
没错 他们来了
Yes. Yes, they're here.
这是我的备胎
These are my spare tyres.
这次旅程路途遥远
Because on a trip like this,
而且车的马力扭矩太大
in a car with that much power and that much torque,
我需要这么多备胎
I am gonna get through some tyres.
-小心树  -不管了
-Tree. -Yeah.
我的后备箱可装不下这么多胎
That lot was not gonna fit in the boot, or trunk, was it?
这才是奢华 这才是大壮游
That is luxury! That is grand touring.
我们只能不情愿地让乡巴佬同事加入
Reluctantly, we agreed to let our vulgar colleague tag along.
哈蒙德 你在故意制造噪音
Hammond, you're deliberately making an irritating noise.
消停会 行吗
Please stop it.
就是故意的
I am, yeah.
我承认 哈蒙德的道奇地狱猫是一辆好车
I will freely admit that Hammond's Dodge Hellcat is a remarkable car.
如果我们是在密尔沃基参加拉力赛 这车再合适不过
It would be perfect if we were at a tractor pull in Milwaukee.
但我们在这
But we're not. We're here.
这是托斯卡纳
And here in Tuscany...
你需要辆这个
...you need one of these.
这是DB9的全新替代车型
This is the all-new replacement for the DB9,
用在此再合适不过
and it is the perfect car for the job.
它甚至配备了三种驾驶模式
It even comes with three running modes.
运动模式 运动+模式
You've got Sport, Sport Plus,
还有个我即将用到的
and the one I'm gonna use.
GT模式
GT.
壮游天地间
Grand Touring.
前面 是一个5.2双涡轮V12引擎
Up front, there's a 5.2 litre, twin-turbocharged V12
能迸发出600匹马力
which produces 600 horsepower.
且马力均匀
And they are smooth horsepower.
如梦似幻
Dreamy horsepower.
很快 你就能买到这车的低配版
In the fullness of time, you'll be able to buy a cheaper version of this car
配有AMG的V8引擎
with an AMG V8.
也是阿斯顿马丁与奔驰合作的产物
It's all part of a deal that Aston have done with Mercedes,
你已经可以看到其结果如何
and you can see evidence of the deal already.
这车有奔驰的换挡杆 奔驰的电子系统
This has got Mercedes switchgear, Mercedes electronics.
甚至连导航都是奔驰的
It's even got Mercedes sat-nav.
不得不说
And I've got to say...
阿斯顿马丁和奔驰
Aston Martin and Mercedes,
是维多利亚女皇嫁给阿尔伯特后
that is the best Anglo-German marriage
最佳的英德联姻
since Queen Victoria married Albert.
但是詹姆斯不同意
James, though, disagreed.
事实上 这才是最佳的英德联姻产物
Actually, this is the best Anglo-German marriage.
这车是完美的
It's perfect, in fact, because it has all the things
它具有标准英国车的所有优点
that we like to think of as being Britishness in a car.
感觉是由一位穿着围裙的男人所制造
The sense that it was made by men in aprons,
体现了其工匠技巧和使用的传统材料
that there are craft skills and traditional materials involved.
而且你还可以享受德国人的高科技
But then you've got the Germans there, with their hi-tech
和他们的制造效率
and their manufacturing efficiency.
绝对的经典之作
It's absolutely wonderful.
它很平和
It's... It's very serene.
我能说出它的不少参数
There are a lot of numbers I could quote on this car.
如最基本的 极速 马力 百公里加速
You know, the usual: top speed, power, 0-60.
之类的废话
All that sort of irrelevant rubbish.
但我不会 因为那太肤浅
But I'm not going to, because that would be, frankly, uncouth.
说到肤浅
Oh, talking of uncouth...
我承认 这不是台安静的车
I'll admit, this is not a quiet car.
它搭载了嗓门又沉又躁的
You've got that big bass rumble and roar
6.2升 V8 HEMI发动机
from the 6.2 litre V8 HEMI.
而且 还附加尖锐狂躁的机增声浪
And over the top, that shrill, manic whine of the supercharger.
这两样都不太环保
Neither is it a particularly economical one.
全油门状态下 84升的油箱
At full chat, it'll chew through its 18.5-gallon fuel tank
13分钟就会用光
in just 13 minutes.
而且 它得吸入大量空气
And, in fact, it needs so much air
来配合汽油消耗
to mix with all that petrol it's drinking,
他们不得不移除一个大灯
they had to remove one of the headlights
换成强制进气口
and replace it with a ram-air intake
给引擎供氧
to feed air to the engine.
所以他们把眼睛换成了鼻子
So they swapped its eye for a nostril.
好处是
The upside of all this, however,
它超快
is that it's extremely fast.
04比保时捷911 GT3还快
It'll do the standing quarter faster than a Porsche 911 GT3,
售价只要五万镑
but it costs, what, £50,000?
詹姆斯那劳斯莱斯可以买五台这车
You could have five of these for one of James May's Rolls-Royces.
又可以炸隧道了
Oh, hello. This looks like a tunnel opportunity.
消停点
Stop doing that!
哈蒙德那车的声音实在是太糟糕了
That is a genuinely horrible noise that Hammond's car's making,
他就是停不下来
and he just keeps doing it.
先猛踩一个踏板 再猛踩另一个
He keeps stamping one pedal, then stamping the other one
就这么头脑简单
in his binary style.
可惜 引擎声不是那台车唯一的问题
Sadly, the engine noise wasn't the only irritation.
这是意大利的加油站巡游么
Is this just going to be a tour of Italy's petrol stations?
这取决于它们之间的距离 不是么
Well, it depends how far apart they are, doesn't it, really?
换角度想 这也是吃小吃的良机
Look at it this way, think of the snacking opportunities.
你为美食而来意大利
You've come to Italy for food.
但不是为了吃薯条
Yeah, but not crisps.
对 不是为了薯条或可怕的美国香肠
No, not crisps and hideous sausages from America.
不一定 每个加油站的餐食都不一样
You don't know. It'll be different in different petrol stations.
-不会的  -会的
-It won't. -It will.
有文艺复兴风格的加油站么
Are there any Renaissance petrol stations we could visit?
或者巴洛克式的
Baroque?
没有 也没有文艺复兴风格的香肠
No. Nor are there any Renaissance sausage rolls in there.
我的天老爷
For God's sake.
在喂饱了他车
Having filled up his car,
和他自己后 我们重新上路
and himself, we were back on the road.
情况通报
A quick situation update.
我正驾车穿越阳光明媚的
I'm driving through sunny It--
闭嘴
Shut up!
坏消息 詹姆斯 前面恐怕又有隧道
Bad news, James. I'm afraid there's a tunnel coming up.
准备好了么
Are you ready? Are you ready?
别来了 哈蒙德 放松享受安静吧
Don't do it, Hammond. Just relax. Enjoy a bit of quiet.
别搞了
Stop it!
这有谁不爱呢
You have got to love that!
很快 我们来到文艺复兴之城 佛罗伦萨
Soon, we arrived in the Renaissance city of Florence,
过去大壮游的必经之地
a traditional stopping point on the Grand Tour of old.
建筑物
Architecture.
佛罗伦萨歌剧院 我们为此而来
Opera di Firenze. This is what we're here for.
我们就是为它而来啊
This is why we're here.
最棒的是
Best of all, though,
詹姆斯和我甩掉了哈蒙德
James and I had managed to lose Hammond.
他那道奇 真把你惹毛了是吧
He's really offending you, isn't he, with his Dodge?
我一般不这么说
Honestly, I wouldn't say this lightly,
我打从心底里
but I have developed a genuine, deep,
深深憎恶那玩意
deep, heartfelt hatred for that thing.
我懂 你快要成粉红豹电影里的德雷福斯督查了
I can tell. You're going to go like Inspector Dreyfus in the Pink Panther films soon.
没错 我都开始抽搐了
You're not wrong. I've developed a twitch.
每当他靠近 我就等着他那愚蠢的噪音
When he comes near me and I'm waiting for that stupid noise it makes,
眼睛也开始颤抖
my eye starts quivering.
就像你在读一本好书的时候
It's like somebody constantly being sick on you
有人一直在你身上呕吐
while you're trying to read a nice book.
分道扬镳之后
As we were on our own,
我和杰里米决定去
Jeremy and I decided to head for
著名的乌菲齐美术馆
the renowned Uffizi Gallery...
欣赏其中珍宝的同时
where we would enjoy a bit of peace and quiet
还可以享受平静与安详
as we appreciated its treasures.
欣赏其中珍宝的同时
where we would enjoy a bit of peace and quiet
还可以享受平静与安详
as we appreciated its treasures.
谁饿了 现在是甜甜圈时间
Who's hungry? Cos it's doughnut time!
太好了
Yeah!
这个给你了
You can have that one!
快撒点糖粉
Put sprinkles on that!
在意大利这随便什么山上浪起来吧
Party on the hill in... wherever we are. Italy.
此地为米开朗基罗广场 弗洛伦萨著名地标
这地方终于有了点生气
Finally bringing some life into this place!
哈蒙德换上新轮胎后
After Hammond had fitted some new tyres...
我和詹姆斯决定放弃乌菲齐
...James and I abandoned our visit to the Uffizi...
把他赶出城去
and escorted him out of town.
哈蒙德 我们在城市的另外一边
Hammond, we could see the smoke from your tyres
都能看到你的胎烟
from the other side of the city.
我知道
I know! I know!
从未有人
Nobody in history has ever,
会开阿斯顿马丁烧胎
ever doughnuted an Aston Martin.
因为车主们都上了年纪
Yeah, they're not young buyers, are they?
不 因为他们优雅且有教养
No, they're refined and cultured.
我真羡慕你 哈蒙德 因为你在车里能看到我的阿斯顿马丁
I envy you, Hammond, cos you get to look at my Aston Martin.
-但你这台车在视觉上有个大问题  -什么
-Yeah, but there's a big problem with it visually. -What?
它是棕色的
It's brown!
这是日落橙
Sunburst Orange is what it is.
杰里米 我要担心吗 大家都听说过这俗语
Jeremy, I shouldn't worry. We all know the expression.
原文为 红色的夜空 牧羊人的爱
早霞不出门 晚霞行千里 之意
棕色的夜空 牧羊人的爱
Brown sky at night, shepherd's delight.
那小伙就去偷东西 你知道么
That bloke's been done for that theft, you know?
糊了一手棕色被抓现行
They caught him brown-handed.
恶搞red-handed
本意小孩子偷糖吃抓了一手红色被抓现行
我开始幻想
I'm starting to imagine
哈蒙德没有脑袋或者皮肤的样子
what Richard Hammond would look like without a head... or skin.
哈蒙德损完马丁的颜色后
Once Hammond had finished rubbishing the Aston's colour,
他开始挑战其性能了
he started to challenge its performance.
哈蒙德现在在我后面 看来他想超车
Hammond is driving along behind me now like he wants to get past.
傻小子
Stupid boy.
你那车的最高车速是多少
What is the top speed of that car of yours?
320公里
199 miles an hour.
我这有322 所以离我远点
Exactly. This will do 200, so back off.
没错 但是你车贵了10万英镑
Well, yes, but it's 100 grand more.
这两公里的提速真贵
That's a very expensive mile an hour.
与其陷入无用的口水战
Rather than get into a pointless war of words,
我决定将计就计
I decided to put Hammond in his place
邀请停在这里
and invited him to pull over here...
穆杰罗赛道
...at the Mugello race track.
为什么带我来这全无文化底蕴的地方
Why have you brought me to this not-at-all cultural place?
因为我想给教教他什么才是真正的速度
Because I want to teach him a lesson about what real speed is.
但他车有700多匹马力
But he's got over 700 horsepower.
大钢牙 007系列电影中的反派人物
我知道 但你记得大钢牙吗
Yes, I know, but you remember Jaws:
戴着钢牙的大家伙
big metal teeth, huge man?
詹姆斯邦德轻松地从窗户把他丢了出去
James Bond simply threw him through a window,
我就要这么教训他
and that's what I'm gonna do to him.
我不参加你介意么
- Do you mind if I don't take part in this?
我来就行
I'll do it.
哈蒙德又换了一套轮胎之后
So, as Hammond had some new tyres fitted... again,
我先下赛道熟悉下情况
I took to the track for some sighting laps.
首先必须说明
Now, let's get one thing straight from the start.
阿斯顿马丁并不是为了跑圈而设计的
Aston Martins are not really designed to do track work.
它们只要好看 就够了
They're designed to look good, and that's it.
这台DB11的底盘
Yes, the chassis on this, the DB11,
是由一名前莲花工程师研发的
was developed by a former Lotus engineer,
厂家明确告诉他
but they actually told him
调校时要更注重舒适性 而非操控性
to tune it more for comfort than handling.
话虽如此
That being said,
但它仍有铝制底盘和空气动力魔法
this has an aluminium chassis and some aero trickery.
后窗的缝隙能导入气流
Air is sucked into holes behind the rear windows
然后从后备箱盖上的通风口导出
and then shot out of a vent on the boot lid,
充当了尾翼的角色
giving me a sort of air rear wing.
给我抓地力 大量抓地力
Giving me grip... a lot of grip.
这车的牵引力控制系统太惊艳了
And the traction control is simply astonishing.
大部分车上 那就像有人用锤子在砸你的头
In most cars, it's like somebody hitting you on the head with a hammer,
但在这 就是
but in this, it's just going,
等下等下等下 搞定
"Erm... Hang on, hang on, hang on." There you go.
天地良心 这车真不错
Bloody hellfire! This is very, very good.
至少碾压哈蒙德那台傻道奇
Certainly it's good enough to be able to totally destroy
是绰绰有余了
Hammond's idiotic Dodge.
这车没有镁制车顶
This does not have a magnesium roof,
或碳纤维传动轴
carbon-fibre prop shaft.
发动机不是铝的 而是铸铁
The engine isn't made from aluminium, it's made from cast iron.
你能感觉到 要条件允许 他们会用石头来造
And you get the impression they'd have made it from stone if they could.
它有的 是充足的动力储备
What it does have is vast reserves of power,
和更充足的个性
and even vaster reserves of character.
这车太欢快了
This thing is just hilarious.
看看他 还有那台棕色的小阿斯顿
Look at him in his little brown Aston,
一切尽在掌握 却毫无乐趣
being all in control, and just not having fun, is he?
又有什么意义呢
I mean, what's the point?
瞎炫耀 还以为我做不到
Showboating. Probably thinks I can't.
不好意思 哈蒙德 这可是一台600马力
Well, I'm sorry, Hammond, this is a 600 horsepower,
后轮驱动的阿斯顿马丁
rear-wheel drive Aston Martin.
所以我关掉了牵引力控制系统
So I turned the traction control off,
释放出了它的本性
and all hell broke loose.
我要像这样漂一整天
It will do this all day.
与此同时
Meanwhile...
大壮游原本的初衷之一
One of the purposes of the original Grand Tour
不仅仅是欣赏和学习
wasn't just to look at things and learn about things.
更是挖掘你的能力
It was also to enhance your capabilities.
你可以去学一些东西
You would learn to do things.
比如写十四行诗
You might do... I don't know, writing sonnets,
演奏乐器 做点地方菜肴之类的
playing musical instruments, regional cooking, maybe.
而我要来尝试一下水彩画
I'm having a go at watercolour painting.
真的能让人心情愉悦
It's absolutely delightful.
除了我的思绪偶尔会被哈蒙德那辆
Apart from my reverie is occasionally interrupted
肌肉车发出的令人厌恶的轰鸣声打断
by the... disgusting bellow of Hammond's muscle car.
哈蒙德同志找来了一辆直升机
Mr. Hammond appears to have organised a helicopter
记录下这场表演
to record the event.
哈哈 克拉克森 超过我呀
Ha-ha, Clarkson! Get past me now!
给你点烟色瞧瞧
Smokescreen you.
你简直蠢到家了 哈蒙德
What a moron you are, Hammond!
给我闪开
Get out of my way!
这不是一项很有文化的行为
This is not a particularly cultural thing to do...
但这很好玩啊
but it is very good fun.
尽管哈蒙德和我一直在制造烟雾
Even though Hammond and I were having a big smoky riot,
但却什么也没学到
we'd learned nothing at all.
所以我们决定要科学一点
So we decided to get scientific
认真做一个计时圈
and do a proper timed flying lap.
这很重要
This matters.
为了英国 也为了欧洲
This is for Britain. This is for Europe.
不要做蠢事
No silly business.
以最快速度跑完这一圈
Let's just get round this as fast as we can.
当计时圈完成了之后
With the flying lap completed,
我们碰头来比较圈速
we met to compare times.
-来吧 你先说 -好吧 2分
-Go on, then. -All right, then. Two...
-我也是 -好的
-Yes. -Yes.
18秒
18 seconds...
-18 -对啊 怎么了 你是多少秒
-18? -Yes. Why, what have you got? What are you?
我也是18 但是
18. B-But...
-你确定不是编出来的吗 -不是 2分18秒
-You're not making that up? -No. Two minutes 18...
嗬
Ooh!
...point 79.
感谢上帝
Oh, thank God for that.
绝对优势 我是35
I'm... It's crushing. Three-five.
什么 这哪叫绝对优势啊
Well, it's hardly crushing, is it?
-这是因为 -我不明白为什么你要接受这个挑战
-No, cos that's... -I don't know why you accepted the challenge.
你多花十万才快了不到半秒
It's less then half a second for your extra 100 grand.
别幸灾乐祸了
Well, hardly a big gloat, is it?
十万英镑只换来了半秒
It's ￡100,000 for half a second
和1.6公里的最高时速
and 1mph top speed.
他们的最大成就就是保持独立240年而已了
240 years of independence and that's the best they can do.
当哈蒙德用烧胎让自己高兴起来
As Hammond cheered himself up with some doughnuts...
然后又换了一组轮胎的时候
...and then another set of tyres...
我去找詹姆斯了
...I went to join James.
见鬼
Oh, shit.
-顺便 你赢了吗 -当然
-Did you beat him, by the way? -Yeah.
好样的
Good man.
当太阳躲入托斯卡纳山背后
As the sun slipped behind the Tuscan hills,
我们也愉快地画了一个多小时
we spent an enjoyable hour or so painting.
可惜好景不长
But then...
你们在干吗
What are you doing?
我正在拆弹 哈蒙德
I'm defusing a bomb, Hammond.
你觉得我还能在干吗
What do you think I'm doing?
我在烤蛋糕
I'm baking a cake.
-你们好像在画画 -我们就是在画画
-It looks like you're painting. -We are painting.
然后哈蒙德决定也要试一试
Hammond then decided he'd like to have a go as well.
好嘞
- Right.
这样
That one.
很快 我们艺术创作完成了
Soon, our art was finished.
我觉得我画的太快了
I think I've rushed mine.
但这还不算什么
Still, could be worse.
在此之前 我以为
It was difficult, before I saw this,
想象出一个比真车更难看的东西很难
to imagine anything more hideous than the actual car.
但你做到了 哈蒙德
But you've done it, Hammond.
你就是为了把这张纸画满吧
It's the way that you've managed to eradicate any sense of place.
是的 我知道
Yeah, I know.
你在抽搐 他在抽搐
Your twitch! He's twitching!
即使在看你这辆车的画
Even when he looks at the picture of your car,
他也会不由自主的抽搐
he's actually twitching!
所有的努力
All of the work...
劳斯莱斯在曜影上的所有努力
All of the work that Rolls-Royce put into that Dawn
让它变得安静 文雅 高尚
to make it quiet and refined and sublime,
以及你的所有期望
and all those things you'd expect,
在你的道奇旁边都变得毫无意义
it all counts for absolutely nothing if it's anywhere near your Dodge,
因为你只能听到它的噪音
because that's all you can hear.
我还要再说两句那辆地狱猫
Do you know something about that Hellcat?
是这样 我做了一些调查
OK, I've done some research into it.
地狱猫参照的是老款克莱斯勒300C
The Hellcat is based on the old Chrysler 300C.
本质上是同一辆车
Underneath, it's the same car.
而300C的原型是90年代的奔驰E级
And the 300C, underneath, is a 1990s Mercedes E-Class.
所以道奇做的就是
So what Dodge has done with that thing,
把700马力放进一辆20年前的出租车里
if they put 700 horsepower in a 20-year-old taxi...
就是这样的
that's what it is.
不管怎样
Anyway,
如果你们想听两个老男人
if you want to listen to two old men
在我玩耍的时候滔滔不绝地说着音乐和歌剧
dribble on about music and opera whilst I have fun,
接下来你们将看到更多
there'll be more of that later on.
而现在是时候看一眼后视镜
But now it's time for us to check our mirrors
然后左转进入唠嗑街了
and make a smooth left into Conversation Street.
是的
It is.
我不得不说
Now... I have to say,
詹姆斯对惠特比之行很是期待
James was very, very excited about coming to Whitby,
因为他听说这里是英国的喷气飞机中心
because he'd heard that it's the centre of the British jet industry.
他期盼着能够花几天的时间
He was very much looking forward to spending
看看协和的旧设计图
a couple of days looking at old drawings of Concord,
但随后他发现
but then he discovered that
所谓的惠特比喷气机其实是这个
Whitby jet is actually this.
看上去像是一块煤
It looks like coal.
jet 喷气式飞机 与 黑玉 同义
-就是煤 -真的吗
-It is coal. -Is it?
是这样的 他们发现
Thing is, though, they've worked out...
显然你不能再烧煤了
Obviouasly, you can't burn coal any more
因为阿尔 戈尔疯了
because Al Gore goes nuts
阿尔 戈尔 前美国副总统 环保主义者
一只北极熊摔了一跤
and a polar bear falls over,
所以他们打磨了下它
so they polish it up
并且说它很珍贵
and then say it's precious.
有意思 我这里有一份从惠特比
That's interesting, this, cos I've got the blurb here
最老的零售商那里拿的简介 上面说
from Whitby's oldest retailer of the stuff, and it says,
不同于其他宝石
"Unlike other gemstones,
黑玉实际上是一种化石木
jet is actually fossilised wood."
是的 因为不同于其他宝石
Yes, because unlike other gemstones,
它是块煤
it's coal.
我知道 但是
Yeah, but...
-但它 -这就是煤 对吧
-But it's... -It's coal, isn't it?
不同于其他宝石 哈蒙德 它还便宜的多
Unlike other gemstones, Hammond, it's a lot cheaper.
真的吗 它确实应该便宜
Well, yes, it would be.
正经点 看 你可以花32英镑买到一枚黑玉戒指
Well, seriously, you can get a jet ring, look, for 32 quid.
10镑就能买一堆了 它是煤啊
You get a sack of it for ten quid. It's coal!
是这样的
Thing is, though...
我们想过这件事
We were thinking the other day,
现在的汽车厂商会用竹子 白蜡树 胡桃木
you know carmakers now they use bamboo, ash, walnut
还有碳纤维去装饰车子
and carbon fibre to decorate bits of a car?
-他们为什么不用黑玉呢 -没错
-Why don't they use jet? -Exactly.
大家都希望车里能有点黑玉
Anybody would like to have some jet in their car.
实际上我们做了个实验 哈蒙德
Actually, we've been doing a little bit of experimenting, Hammond.
我做了一个样品 这是用黑玉做档头的变速杆
I've made a prototype. This is a gearstick with a jet knob...
真的很棒
...on the top. It's brilliant.
我还没给它抛光 但是当你换挡的时候
I mean, it's not polished yet, but you change gear.
它会把你的手弄脏
It does make your hand a bit dirty.
话虽如此 但它是个很好用的提示器
But, no, that's a handy reminder. It is.
没错 你说的完全正确
Exactly. No, you're absolutely right 'cause you know,
有时候当你开着一辆不熟悉的车在高速公路上
sometimes you drive an unfamiliar car, you're on the motorway
你会想 我挂到六档了吗
and you think, "Oh, did I change into sixth?
噢 挂了
Yeah, I did."
有一些话我想在唠嗑街里说
Here's some conversation... for Conversation Street.
有个坏消息 我们的国家正面临一个问题
Erm... Bad news. There is a problem right now in this country.
学习驾驶的人不够多
Not enough people are learning to drive. Seriously.
在2007年 有超过16000场驾驶考试
In 2007, just over 16,000 driving tests were conducted.
但去年这个数字跌到了4650
Last year, that had dropped to 4,650.
这是事实 在不到十年的时间里
That is a true fact. In less than ten years,
从16000下降到了4000
16,000 down to 4,000.
我知道为什么会这样
And I know why.
因为现在这些刚进入社会的孩子们
It's because kids leave school these days,
他们不知道希特勒是谁
they've no idea who Hitler was,
他们不会算数
they can't add up.
他们只知道车是不好的
They just know cars are bad.
已经被洗脑了
cars are bad, cars are bad, cars are bad.
然后当他们离开学校
Then, when they do get out of school, after what--
毕业之后
after school's finished,
看到到处都是测速相机 交通拥堵
they go around and see speed cameras, traffic jams,
限制机动车路权的标志牌
signs saying "Please don't overtake cyclists"
然后就会想 车有什么用
and think, "What's the point?"
我完全没必要学车 用优步就行了
"No point learning to drive. I might as well just use Uber."
没错 如果我是一个汽车制造商
Exactly. If I were a carmaker,
我会用百分之一百二十的努力
I would be fighting like a Kilkenny cat
来确保我做的每辆车
to make sure every car I made
都尽可能的有趣和惊艳
was as interesting and as amazing as possible.
然而实际上 雷诺做出来的却是科雷嘉
But instead... Renault, they give us the KADJAR.
有多少孩子
How many children...
有多少孩子会说 如果我很努力学习又好好做功课
How many children will say, "If I work really hard and do my homework,
没准将来有一天 我会拥有一辆科雷嘉
one day, maybe, I can have a KADJAR"?
因为这就是他们从小到大看到的车
Cos that's the car they grow up seeing.
还可能更糟 日产Juke
Worse still, Nissan Juke.
-你真的很讨厌Juke -是的 我讨厌它
-You really hate the Juke. -No, I hate it.
-他真的是非常讨厌 -没错 我讨厌它
-No, he genuinely hates... -No, I hate...
我觉得它就不应该存在
I object to it existing. It shouldn't exist.
我厌恶它
I loathe it.
在高速公路上你会看到那两只愚蠢的
On the motorway, you see them with their stupid,
像虫子一样的眼睛
like, double bug eyes.
自鸣得意的小
Smug little...
要是看到它 我会抓狂的
If I see one, I'm mad.
我控制不住我自己
I can't help myself.
如果你有一辆 很抱歉 我知道这样说不好
And it's cruel, and I'm sorry if you're in one.
但说真的 当我看到那辆车
But I do, I see them.
我恨它
"I hate..."
他就是这样的 有天我开车带着他
He does. I was driving along with him the other day...
我正在和他讲故事
I was busy telling him a story,
他却在朝窗外喊
and he was looking out the window going,
我讨厌你 我讨厌你
"I hate you! I hate you!"
我讨厌它们
I hate them.
现在英国在售的最无聊的车是什么
What's the most boring car on sale in Britain today?
这是个好问题
That's a good question.
棕色的阿斯顿马丁
Brown Astons!
-哈哈哈 -刚刚谁说的
Ha-ha-ha! Ha-ha-ha! - Who said that?
出去 给我出去
Get out. Get out.
保安 杀了他
Security, kill him.
棕色阿斯顿个...
"Brown Astons" my...
听着 如果我是大众的老板
I tell you what, if I were the boss of Volkswagen,
我会找到那个设计师
I'd go and find the man who did...
那辆很高的高尔夫叫什么来着
What's that tall Golf called?
那个 SV
Oh, the SV.
对 SV 那辆专门给戴大礼帽的人
SV, that's it. The one that's like a Golf,
设计的高尔夫
but for people who have stovepipe hats.
然后用轮胎撬棍打死他
And I would bludgeon him with a tyre iron.
你为什么要这么做 这辆车没人会买
"Why did you do that? Nobody wants one!"
坦白说 我觉得大众正面临着更棘手的问题
Just to be fair, I think VW have bigger concerns at the moment.
好吧 接下来我要说说Oxford Ring Road
OK, I want to talk about the Oxford Ring Road.
我知道离这里很远 大家也都看不见
I know it's miles away from here and from anybody watching,
但我想说的是 在过去两年内
but the thing is, OK, for the last two years,
这两个环岛一直在缩小
they've been working on shrinking - slightly shrinking -
并增加了一些信号灯
two roundabouts and putting some traffic lights up.
可你们知道这项工程的预算是多少吗
Now, do you know how much the budget was for that job?
呃 两个环形路口 就算一个一万
Er... Two roundabouts, ten grand a roundabout.
一共两万吧
I'd say 20 grand overall.
900万镑
￡9 million.
-真的吗 900万 -是的 900万
-Million? Nine million? -Nine million.
你们能想象承包商知道消息后脸上的表情吗
Can you imagine the builder's face when he came out of that meeting?
他们竟然要给我900万
"They're gonna give me nine million quid
就为了缩小两个环岛
to shrink a couple of roundabouts!"
所以他才用了两年的时间
Well, that's why it's taken him two years.
要让这项工程看起来像是900万的规模
He had to make it look like nine million quid's worth.
确实很难
"Really difficult."
一点没骗人
This is not a word of a lie.
900万镑 可以买2800平米的豪宅
￡9 million will buy you a 30,000-square-foot house,
就像这样
OK, like this.
这才是900万镑的工程
That is a nine-million-quid house to build.
你可以用那900万镑建一座这样的房子
You can have that or two shaved roundabouts...
或者两个环岛
for your nine million quid.
不不不 不是的
No. No, actually. No.
因为 我说的都是实话
Because - and this, again, is not a word of a lie -
几个月前 这项目承包商
a few months ago, builder man -
我估计他是跟别人打赌了
and it must have been a bet -
他回到了议会 然后说
he went back to the council and he said,
我还需要一百万镑
"I need another million quid."
议会给他了吗
And they paid?
给了 竟然真的给了
And they paid! They paid!
没准他是这么说的 我把铲子弄坏了
He probably shuffled in. "I broke me spade."
能再给我一百万吗 没问题 乐意效劳
"Another million?" "Yes, of course. Happy to."
我能再说两句宝马吗
Can I be cross for a moment with BMW?
我们都拦不住你 说吧
It'll be difficult to stop you. Yes.
是这样 宝马在去年公布了这辆车
The thing was, last year they introduced this.
他们放出了图片 然后说 看呐
They showed... They went, "Look at that."
大家的反应都是 太棒了
And everybody went, "That is fantastic!"
这是一辆向1972年CSL Batmobile致敬的车
It's an homage to the old CSL Batmobile from '72.
大家都在问 什么时候开始造
Everyone was going, "When will you make it?"
宝马说不造 就是让你们看我们多厉害
"We're not. It's just to show you what we could make."
那他们放出这张图片做什么
Why did they show us?
-别这么吊人胃口 -说得没错
- Just don't do that! - Yeah, exactly.
实际上那个并不重要
Actually, no, it doesn't matter,
因为他们之后又发布了这个
because they've come up with something else instead.
你们看 这辆车是用来向
This look. This is actually an homage
左边那辆宝马2002致敬的
to the original 2002, which is the old car on the left,
我觉得这车看上去简直美极了
and that, I think, actually looks pretty fab.
-确实是 他们会造出来吗 -不会
-It does. Are they gonna make it? -No.
那为什么要给我们看
Well, why show it to us, then?
瞧我们能造这么好的车 但就是不造
"Look what we could make but we're not."
幸好宝马不负责紧急救援
It's a good job BMW don't run the emergency services, isn't it?
看呐 你从那海岸漂过来挺远了吧
"Oh, look! You have drifted a long way from shore there, haven't you?
我们可以用快艇拉着你走
We could drag you back behind our speedboat."
-你们会吗 -不 就是告诉你我们能这么干
"Will you?" "No. No, we just wanted you to know that we could."
宝马就是在戏屌
What they're being is prick-teasers.
噢你不能这么说
Oh, you can't say that.
我觉得你不能说那个词
I don't think you can say that.
我也觉得你不能这么说
I'm not sure you can say that.
你能说戏屌吗？
Can you say "prick-tease"?
-耍鸡 -现在不让这么说了吗
- A cock-tease! - Is it allowed today?
耍鸡也一样啊 你只是换了个词
"Cock-tease"? That's no different. You've just changed the name!
只不过是说屌的不同方式
It's a different way of saying "prick" or "dick".
那还可以直接说玩茎 都一样
You could have said "penis tease". It doesn't matter!
唠嗑街开始变得有点污了
Conversation Street's taken a really bad turn.
重点是我觉得宝马不应该再这样了
The point I'm trying to make is BMW must stop doing that.
不管 不管这是什么
Whatever... Whatever it was.
听着 如果我们有一块Grand Tour奖牌
Now, if we had a Grand Tour medal,
我们并没有 如果有的话
and we don't, but if we did,
我知道第一个应该颁给谁
I know who the first recipient would be.
因为我们那天听到了这个惊人的故事
Cos we heard this amazing story the other day.
你们都知道测速车吧
You know speed camera vans?
停在路边 把窗户涂黑
Sit at the side of the road, blacked out windows,
人民公仆坐在里面看黄片
civil servant sitting inside watching YouPorn. OK?
本来就是 等着有人超速
That's what it is. Waiting for someone to trip his camera.
有一天 一个人偷偷
Now, someone, the other day,
溜到了测速车的后面
snuck up behind the speed-camera van,
把车牌摘了下来
quietly undid its number plates
再装到自己的车上
put them on his own car
然后以每小时160公里的速度开了过去
and drove past at 100 miles an hour.
我想说 这真是我听过的最有意思的事
I mean... literally the funniest thing ever!
干得漂亮 先生
Well done, you, sir.
太漂亮了
Top work.
-简直了 -我喜欢
- Absolutely... - I love that.
这件事干得真是太漂亮了
That is top, top work.
我能说说阿尔法罗密欧的Quadrifoglio吗
Can I talk about the Alfa Romeo Quadrifoglio?
-不能 -为什么
-No. -Why?
因为我们该回归正题了
Because we've got to get back to our film.
今晚我们在意大利大壮游
Tonight we are on a Grand Tour of Italy.
詹姆斯开着一辆劳斯莱斯
There's James in a Rolls-Royce,
杰里米开着一辆阿斯顿马丁
Jeremy in an Aston Martin,
我开着一辆道奇地狱猫 以及两辆装满轮胎的卡车
and me in a Dodge Hellcat with two trucks full of tyres
所以我可以随时随地玩烧胎
so I can do doughnuts whenever I want.
没错 接下来的第二天
Yes, and we pick up the action on day two
多亏了他 这趟路程
of what was becoming, thanks to him,
越来越见鬼了
the journey from hell.
当太阳在寂静且雾气朦胧的
As the sun rose over the silent,
意大利乡间升起之时
misty Italian countryside...
好了咱们出发吧
OK, let's get these out.
哈蒙德在酒店停车场
...and Hammond extricated his entourage
解救了他的随行人员
from the hotel car park...
而詹姆斯把劳斯莱斯的顶棚放了下来
...James lowered the roof on his Rolls-Royce.
-早 -早上好
-Morning. -Morning.
这是 沉静的芭蕾舞
That is the "silent ballet".
-你的卡车一点也不沉静 -没说那个
-There's nothing silent about your lorries, Hammond. -No, not those.
劳斯莱斯就是这么形容
That's how Rolls-Royce themselves describe the roof
顶棚开合的 你看
going up and down, in this, look.
-什么 沉静的芭蕾舞 -对 就是这么写的
-What, "silent ballet"? -"Silent ballet", that's what they say.
他们还说 曜影的手感性欲撩人
They also talk about "the Dawn provides an erotic tingle on the skin."
-等一下 -他们就是这么说的
-Whoa! -This is all their words.
-这真是劳斯莱斯的 -没错 这是他们的手册
-Actual Rolls-Royce...? -This is their words. Yeah, this is their bumf.
他们还说
They also say,
这车赌场生活方式的现代演绎
"The car is a contemporary take on the casino lifestyle.
-专为吸引那些人
It is intended to attract... people."
哪些人
-What sort of people? -People...
那些喜欢用安全带的人
People who put their seatbelts on?
没错 穿脱安全带的人
Exactly, people who put their seatbelts on and off
同时尽享人生自由与精妙
and relish both freedom and sophistication.
-赌场生活方式 -赌场生活方式
-"Casino lifestyle"?-Casino lifestyle.
怎么了
What?
我们能走了吗
Can we go?
你安全带系上了没有
Have you got your seatbelt on?
我们接着就出发了
We then set off
同时决定对车进行更多的路测
and decided to do a bit more road testing of our cars.
我先说说阿斯顿马丁的内饰
I began by talking about the Aston Martin's interior.
优点是
On the upside,
阿斯顿马丁重编了奔驰的电子设备
Aston Martin have reprogrammed the Mercedes electronics
所以提示警告音不那么 德系
so the warning beeps and buzzers are now less...Germanic.
比如你不系安全带
If you don't put your seatbelt on,
你会听到矜持的咳嗽
for example,you get a discreet cough.
而不是高音喇叭
rather than a klaxon
和一声大吼  危险
and somebody shouting,"Achtung!"
Achtung 德语
缺点是 其余的地方
On the downside is everything else.
中控中间看上去就像
Er... The centrepiece of this dashboard here looks like a...
该怎么说呢  像女性体征
How can I put this?...like a lady part.
至于门线这里 更是丑的可怕
And then the door lining here, well, it's just hideous.
就像足球运动员的厨房台面
It look like a footballer's...kitchen worktop.
很烦人 阿斯顿这台车造得这么好
It's annoying, cos Aston have done such a good job with the rest of this car.
我都惊呆了
I was staggered
昨天它在赛道上的表现
by how good it was at the track yesterday.
而它就被这可怕的内饰拖累了
And yet, they've let it all down with this ghastly interior.
在地狱猫中 汉克 J 哈蒙德堡
In the Hellcat, Hank J Hammondberger
并没有在意装配品质
hadn't noticed the quality of the fixtures and fittings.
只是忙着捣鼓小玩意
He was too busy playing with the toys.
啊来看看这些
Oh, now, look at all of this.
计时器 仪表盘
Timers, gauges...
噢
Oh.
我的性能模式屏幕
In my performance mode screen,
我可以测量 G力 刹车距离
I can measure G-forces, braking distance,
反应时间 四分之一英里计时
reactions times, quarter-mile timer,
八分之一英里计时 圈速记录
eighth-of-a-mile timer, lap history.
太棒了
It's brilliant!
无关紧要
Irrelevant twaddle.
"Irrelevant twaddle."
我刚刚看见了我的平均油耗
Oh, I've just seen my average MPG.
是多少
What is it?
42.8
6.6
百公里油耗42.8升
Six miles to the gallon?
我觉得这应该算胃口不错
I like to think of it as a healthy appetite.
詹姆斯你的劳斯莱斯的油耗怎么样
How many miles to the gallon has your Rolls-Royce been doing, James May?
过去的48小时里是百公里18升
15.7 in the last 48 hours.
我的车是百公里13.5 升
Mine's been doing 21 miles to the gallon.
因为它无聊 更因为它是棕色的
That's cos it's boring and that's because it's brown!
又来
Oh, no.
就这样 公路测试结束
And, with that, the road test ended
又一天的哈蒙德式讨人厌开始了
and another day of Hammond-based irritation began.
就这样 公路测试结束
And, with that, the road test ended
又一天的哈蒙德式讨人厌开始了
and another day of Hammond-based irritation began.
天上飞过棕色的鸟
There'll be brown birds over...
它让我棕色的眼睛更棕了
Don't it make my brown eyes brown?
是橙色
It's orange!
我们在另一座加油站见面了
You join us at another petrol station.
我是不要加油 但猜猜谁要
I don't need any,but guess who does.
这车给鸟类学家再好不过
This car is excellent for ornithologists.
这么驾驶太安静了 我听的到鸟的歌唱
It's so quiet going along here, I can listen to the birdsong.
你好 詹姆斯
Hello, James.
噢老天爷啊
Oh, for God's sake.
派对按钮
Party button!
别这么干了
Stop doing that!
停
Stop it!
走开啦
Go away!
我真担心德里弗司探长的神志
I genuinely am worried about the sanity of Chief Inspector Dreyfus.
很多烦人的里程过后
Many frustrating miles later,
我们来到壮游的下一个目的地
we reached the next stop on our Grand Tour:
摩德纳地区
the region around Modena,
世上最伟大的三个车厂的家
which is home to three of the world's greatest carmakers.
当哈蒙德忙于
And, while Hammond sped off
了解兰博基尼历史的时候
to give his cultural take on Lamborghini's history...
哦老天 这简直淫荡
Oh, my God. That is pure filth.
我和詹姆斯
...James and I went off
去给他买了个送别礼物
to buy a goodbye present for him.
我觉得剪刀门让我饥渴了起来
I think scissor doors actually make me horny.
当他结束 布莱恩斯威尔 例行活动的时候
And when he'd finished his Brian Sewell routine...
Brian sewell 英国当代艺术评论家
我们赠予了他礼物
...we met up to hand it over.
我们为了你做了这个
We have had it done for you.
-它太棒了-我知道
-It's brilliant! -I know.
它的风格来源于
It's in the style, actually,
十八世纪意大利艺术家 蓬皮欧巴托尼
of an 18th-century Italian artist called Pompeo Batoni,
他活的很滋润
who made a pretty good living
给来壮游的美国人画画赚了很多
out of painting visiting Americans on the Grand Tour
让他们看起来像是优雅
and making them look like refined,
文明的英国绅士
cultured English gentleman.
把它当这次旅程的纪念品吧
Yeah. Think of it as a souvenir of your trip.
谢谢 但纪念品是旅程最后才拿的
Thank you. Except a souvenir is what you get at the end of a trip.
-没错 -嗯
-Yeah, exactly. -Erm...
当哈蒙德奋力将画放进车里
While Hammond struggled to get the painting in his car
踏上漫漫回英路时
for the long trip back to England...
嗯
Er...
詹姆斯和我独自开向了意大利的荣耀
...James and I set off alone into the glory that is Italy.
难以形容 看这景色呀
Oh, my word. Look at that view.
我的天呐
Holy moley!
当晚在维罗纳
That evening in Verona,
我们在米其林餐厅里美餐
we dined well at a Michelin-starred restaurant,
然后我们去看了一个叫 卡门 的东西
and then we went to see something called Carmen,
Carmen 卡门 字面意义也可读为汽车人
但那和我们期待的东西完全不一样
which wasn't at all what we were expecting.
他没回家对吧
He hasn't gone home, has he?
第二天早上天一亮我们就起了
The next morning, we were up at first light
想要再次逃脱
to attempt another escape.
詹姆斯 他的房间在这里
James... that's his room.
这车有悄声启动功能 但我不会用
This has a quiet-start facility on it, but I don't know how it works.
摁它
Push it.
我可以这车很安静
I could... It's really quiet.
你启动吧 你没问题
You start... You'll be all right.
别吵
Don't bong!
很神奇不是么
That's amazing, isn't it?
大概每秒点火80次
That's firing 80 times a second, roughly.
啊没有噪音
Ah, no noise.
我可以就这样开出去
I can just drive out of here.
哦你们好 车出问题啦
Oh, hello! Car trouble?
-对啊-典型阿斯顿你瞧
- Yeah.- Typical Aston, you see!
这抛锚了
It's broken down.
你得抓紧时间了
You haven't got long to get it going
因为我眨眼就换好衣服 然后出发
cos I'll be down again in a second, changed and ready to roll.
嗨呀
Ya-ha!
当哈蒙德上去 风干他一身汗的时候
Whilst Hammond was upstairs, chiselling off his sweat...
詹姆斯和我开始跑路
...James and I made a run for it.
同时 防止他在高速上追到我们
And, in case he caught up with us on the motorway,
我们便采取了预防措施
we took some precautions.
这是天才之作
This is the work of a genius.
我们现在从哈蒙德先生眼前消失无踪了
We are now protected from Mr Hammond completely.
詹姆斯的脑袋有点影响大局 不过也有办法
James's head was a bit of a problem with this plan, but we've solved it.
观众们 如果没认出来不要惊慌 是我
Don't worry if you don't recognise me, viewers. It's me.
问题是 哈蒙德认得出来吗
The question was, would Richard Hammond recognise him?
理查德哈蒙德来了 我只要目视前方
Here comes Richard Hammond. Just look straight ahead.
目视前方
Look straight ahead.
真相是
And the answer was...
不能看
Not looking.
妈蛋 他正朝我招手呢
Oh, God. He's waving at me!
那他就算是发现我们了是吧
Well, he's clocked us, hasn't he?
我觉得那车就是被飞石打了
I think you're better off getting stone chips than looking like that.
也比他包成那样好看
than looking like that.
救命 救命 我快包不住了
Mayday. Mayday. I'm disintegrating.
就在詹姆斯撕掉他自己的包装纸
Whilst James unwrapped himself
理查德穿过被毁的肖像画加油的时候
and Richard filled up through his ruined present,
我突然灵机一动
I had another brainwave.
我打算把他引到维琴察的市中心去
I'm gonna lead him into the centre of Vicenza, yeah?
嗯
Yes.
我刚发了个推 然后也转到了Facebook上
I've sent out a tweet, and I put this on Facebook,
告诉大家理查德哈蒙德会现身市中心广场
saying that Richard Hammond will be appearing in the main square, OK?
啊 所以到时候他一出现
-Yes. -So he gets out.
他就会被围住 没错
-He's mobbed. -Yes.
-我们趁机溜走  -很好
-We scarper -Very good.
-明白吗 -我喜欢
-OK? -I like it.
你是用意大利语发的吗 是
-Have you done it in Italian? -Yes.
那就好
Oh, good.
唯一不妥的 我犯了个小错误
Only thing is, I've made a slight mistake.
我这上边写的是理查德哈蒙德会
I have said here that Richard Hammond will be -
我本来想说 现身
I wanted to say "appearing" but I've put
结果打成了 献身
"exhibiting himself".
这样更能吸引人啊
Well, it'll get a crowd.
上路后 我就开始了计划的实施
Back on the move, I put my plan into action.
哈蒙德 我们要不从这下高速吧
I thought we'd turn off the motorway here, Hammond.
维琴察有个专门烧胎画圈的地方
Vicenza's gota doughnuting area in it.
是吗
Has it?
对 那里没有古建筑
Yeah, no old statues.
有的只是星巴克 麦当劳 和唐恩甜甜圈
There's Starbucks,McDonald's, Dunkin' Donuts.
我说的没错吧 詹姆斯
I'm right, aren't I, James?
我记得维琴察他们有支橄榄球队来着
I think they've got an American football team
是吧
haven't they, in Vicenza?
是的 维琴察红熊队
They have, the Vicenza Red Bears.
好
OK.
我们就去看看
We'll have a little mooch about.
很快 我们就离市中心不远了
Soon, we were approaching the centre of the town.
只要那群人能够
I just need a crowd big enough
缠住他20分钟 我就够了
to keep him occupied for 20 minutes.
我不知道能有多少人看到我发的推
I don't know how many people will have read my tweet.
估计也就几百吧
A couple of hundred.
和我估计的差的不多
I was nearly right.
我的天
Oh, my God.
我错了
This has gone really wrong.
这回真玩大了 杰里米
-This has gone so spectacularly wrong. -Jeremy!
我滴妈
Oh, my word!
你们好 这是有什么活动吗
Hello. Is there an event on?
你要找的是哈蒙德
It's Mr Hammond you're looking for.
哈蒙德开的是那辆道奇
Mr Hammond is in the Dodge.
哦 这有点吓人呦
Oh, this is unnerving.
这一直都这么热闹吗
Is it always this busy here?
还是今天有什么事啊
What's going on today?
快看 我们出来了
Look at that, we're free
而哈蒙德还在里面困着
and Hammond is stuck.
太棒了
Yes. Yes.
我们出来啦
We're out.
哈蒙德完喽
Hammond is doomed!
他完蛋喽
He's doomed!
当哈蒙德还以为
Leaving Hammond in what he thought
他到了意大利的肌肉车圣地的时候
was the muscle-car capital of Italy...
他们喜欢听飙高转
They like a rev.
他们还真好这一口
They do like a rev here.
我和詹姆斯已经出城了
...James and I headed out of town.
好的 离威尼斯只有37公里了
Right, good. Venice, 23 miles away.
凭心而论
I think it's fair to say
这趟旅程确实是惨不忍睹
that this entire trip has been a total disaster.
但这辆阿斯顿马丁却表现十分惊艳
But the Aston Martin has been the complete opposite.
在赛道上 它比我想得要好太多太多
It was much, much better than I thought it was going to be on the track.
在公路上 它又是难以置信的安静和舒适
It's staggeringly civilised and quiet on the road.
它真心是辆顶级的GT车
It really is a superb grand tourer,
而且还漂亮的要命
and it is achingly pretty.
尤其是这身橙色的车漆
Especially with this beautiful orange paintwork.
或许杰里米或许已经对他的棕色阿斯顿暗生情愫
Jeremy may have been won over by his brown Aston,
而我则是完全迷上了我的劳斯莱斯
but I was truly smitten with the Rolls-Royce.
一台劳斯莱斯究竟意味着什么
What is it about a Rolls-Royce?
许多人都说这不是一辆爱车之人会喜欢的车
A lot of people would say this isn't a car-lover's car.
不运动 没活力
It's not sporty, it's not dynamic,
没有模式选择
it doesn't have modes for you to set.
连想换档都不行
You can't even change the gears.
你只能选择是前进还是倒车
You can only put it in forward or reverse.
可我恰好觉得爱车之人一定会喜欢它
And yet, I think this is a car for people who love cars,
因为它能带给你一种完全不同的驾驶体验
because it gives you an entirely different driving experience.
世界上没有那辆车能够像劳斯莱斯一样
There is no other car that's quite like a Rolls-Royce,
这么溺爱般的保护着你
no other car that cossets you in the same way.
这是一辆会对你好的车
This is a car that is kind to you.
我觉得你开着这辆车就不可能会生气
I think it is actually impossible to be unhappy if you're driving this car.
你看看我都经历些什么
And look at what I've had to put up with
理查德哈蒙德 理查德哈蒙德
Richard Hammond and Richard Hammond
还有理查德哈蒙德 道奇地狱猫
Richard Hammond, the Dodge Hellcat
以及理查德哈蒙德 和道奇地狱猫
而我依然很开心
and I'm still happy.
到达威尼斯的时候 我们心情大好
As we arrived in Venice, we were in good spirits.
第二天早上
And, the next morning,
我们做了前人们
we did what all our predecessors
在这大壮游时都会做的事
on the Grand Tour would have done.
我们在水上享受了当地的美景
We took in the sights from the water.
没有哈蒙德的日子太爽了
It's so nice without Hammond.
昨天晚饭
Dinner last night...
点餐的时候没人在旁边说
Nice to order food without somebody going
你们有薯片吗 的感觉太好了
Have you got any chips?"
没错 还有 番茄酱在哪
Yeah. "Where's the ketchup?"
他这辈子都不可能从那个广场出来了
He is never, ever going to get out of that square.
这辈子
I mean never.
我估计他已经被踩死了或者被扯碎了
I assume he's been crushed to death by now, or torn apart.
看见了吗
Have you seen that?
嗯 真有病
-Yeah. -What a moron.
一艘不合时宜的棕色汽艇
An inappropriate brown powerboat.
橙色
Orange.
这东西让开吗这 我还挺吃惊的
Is that allowed round here? I'm surprised, actually.
伙计们
Lads!
真是粗野
What a yob.
我以为他的地狱猫就够糟了
I thought his Hellcat was bad.
哈蒙德 住手
Hammond, no.
你这样真不合适 哈蒙德 别这样
That's really inappropriate, Hammond. Don't do that.
这船非常容易晃 别
This is very wobbly.
别 别 哈蒙德
Don't... Don't do that, Hammond.
有谁饿了吗 谁想吃甜甜圈
Who's hungry? Who's for doughnuts?
哈蒙德 停下
Hammond, stop it!
水上甜甜圈
Yah! Water doughnut!
停下
Stop it!
哈蒙德 哈蒙德
Hammond! Hammond!
咋啦
What?
大壮游 明年还可以再搞一次
Grand Tour. We can do it again next year.
怎么样 明年要不要再搞一次
Next year? Do it again next year?
你不光是把我俩
Not only did you knock us into
晃进了威尼斯的污水里
the sewage-infested waters of Venice...
你还把我们给你的礼物拦腰折断
you cut the present we gave you in half.
不等一会 没有
No, hang on a minute.
它就像是一个只有两块的拼图一样
No, it was only like a two-piece jigsaw puzzle
我又把它拼起来了
and I put it back together again.
你看 就在那
Look, there it is.
怎么样 完好如初吧
See? Perfect.
哈蒙德 干嘛
-Hammond? -Yes.
人家艺术馆没人会为了把艺术品搬上楼
Art galleries do not saw artworks in half
而把它们锯成两半 你个智障
just to get them up the stairs, you moron.
总之 听着 在我们进入下一个板块之前
Anyway, listen, before we move on,
我能再多说几句关于阿斯顿马丁的吗
can I just say something about that Aston Martin?
不是为了惹你俩生气 我是真心的
Not to wind you two up. I genuinely mean this.
这真是辆好车
It's an amazing car.
我承认它方向盘是方的
I know the steering wheel is square.
-它还是棕色的 -没错
-And it was brown -Yes.
内饰也不漂亮
And I know the interior wasn't very nice,
但是它真的打动我了
but, genuinely, it's affected me.
在我回来之后它
It's been living up here
它就一直在我脑海中挥之不去
ever since I got back.
哎说到脑海啊
And talking of up here,
现在应该是明星脑碰脑时间了
it's now time to play Celebrity Brain Crash.
是时候让明星们
Yes, it's time for a top celebrity
在我们可怕的测试中
to try their hand at our
展现他们的技巧
fearsome test of skill,co-ordination
协调性和观察力
and observation.
我要解释一下
Now, so far, I should explain,
目前没有明星成功踏进我们的帐篷
no celebrity has actually made it to the tent.
没错 他们都死了
No, they've all died.
但这次让我们一起祈祷吧
Yes, but our fingers are crossed for this week,
因为这次的嘉宾是位巨星
because our guest is a huge star.
他参演过碟中谍
You'll have seen him in Mission Impossible,
星际迷航
Star Trek,
僵尸肖恩
Shaun Of The Dead,
热血警探
Hot Fuzz,
他今天会在这谈论他新电影
and he's here to talk about his new movie -
由斯皮尔伯格导演的 一级玩家
Spielberg movie - Ready Player One .
女士们先生们 西蒙 佩吉
Ladies and gentlemen, we've got Simon Pegg!
他就在那
And there he is.
There he is, ladies and gentlemen,
和他的可爱多
with his Cornetto.
西蒙的血与冰淇淋系列电影
永远都有一个甜筒
Always a Cornetto.
他和外星人干过仗
He's battled aliens,
和僵尸打过架
he's battled zombies,
所以他应该能顺利地
he should have no problem at all
在这美丽小镇溜达吧
with a short stroll through this pretty little town.
他电影里我最喜欢 保罗
Of all his films, it's Paul that I like best.
-对 那是一部很出色的电影
-I think that stands out.
-保罗简直是泰迪熊的祖先
Paul was the forerunner of Ted, really.
-没错 -它先出来的
-It was -It was first. It came first.
我最喜欢热血警探 那打斗场面
Hot Fuzz  It's Hot Fuzz for me, just because of the fight scenes.
他来了 他到桥上了
There he is He's on the bridge.
看起来海鸥要找他麻烦
- It looks like he's being hassled by seagulls.
海鸥想要他的甜筒
They're after his Cornetto, I think.
对它们冲着 噢
Yeah, they're after his.. Oh!
噢
Oh!
啊天啊
Oh, God.
我们什么也做不了
There's literally nothing we can do.
我们要背骂名了
We're gonna get a reputation.
就是说他来不了 对吧
Does that mean he's not coming on then?
呃 詹姆斯
Well, James...
他掉了下去
...he fell into the harbour,
北海刺骨的海水正灌满他的肺
and the icy North Sea waters are now filling his lungs.
对 他来不了了
It's a no He's not coming on.
哦天啊
Oh, God...
瞧啊 我
Well, look, I...
我预料到会有这事发生
-Oh -I anticipated something like this.
-是吗 -嗯
-Did you? -Yes.
所以我另有个填补时间的方法
And so I prepared something else we can do to fill the time.
是这样 你们知道
It's this. You know Google have been
谷歌正在造无人车吧
trying to build a self-driving car?
他们造了七年
For seven years they've been at it.
我们这有张照片
We've got a picture of it
它看起来十分丑陋
It's absolutely hideous.
所以我就想啊 这能有多难
I was thinking, "Well, how hard can it be?"
天啊
- Oh, God.
十天前我就决定试一试
Ten days ago I thought, "I'll give it a bash," okay?
而且我成功完成了
And I've already finished it.
-是吗 -没错它就在这
-Have you? -Yes, it's here.
-是吗 -没错
-Is it? -Yes, it's here.
让我把它带进来 用手机控制哦
Let's bring it out It's phone-operated.
-啊 等等 -啥
-So, erm.. Hang on. Just set... -What?
没 准备好了 往右 前进
No, here it comes Right, forwards.
前进
Forwards.
别让北海的悲伤
Please try not to be distracted
扰乱前进的方向
by the harrowing scenes.. of...
往左 往左
Left, left.
往前
Straight.
西蒙毫无生气的尸体
...the harrowing scenes of Simon's lifeless corpsebeing fished
被钓出水面的悲伤一幕
from the harbour.
我知道有些观众十分悲伤
I know that's upsetting for some people.
后面的观众们 让个道
Right, we need to make a bit of a a hole in the crowd back here,
因为我要把它带进我们的帐篷了
cos I'm gonna bring it into the tent studio
让你们膜拜机智的我
so you can see how brilliant I've been.
直走
Forwards.
认真的
- Really?
这就是很厉害嘛
That is brilliant!
这
-It's..
鼓掌吧大伙
-Cheer, everybody.
左拐 左拐
Left. Left. Left.
看着真丑-往左 直走
-It's hideous! -Left. Forwards.
-太丑了 等等
-It's... So, hold on
-停
-Stop. Stop.
这一点都不天才 太丑了 真的
It's not brilliant It's hideous, is what it is.
你怎么能说它丑呢
How can you say it's hideous?
这可是原味山寨的谷歌设计
I've copied Google's styling completely.
这是个化粪池吗
Is that a septic tank?
没错
Yes, it is.
切了一半 然后扣上了这个躺椅
Cut in half, and then I've mounted on the top this chaise longue,
所以拥有者就可以舒舒服服的躺着了
so the owner can recline in great comfort.
好好好 所以它到底怎么运作的
Yeah, yeah How does it actually work?
展示天才想法的时候到了
Brilliantly.
这下面有一个小摄像头
Down here, a very small little camera.
给内部系统采集路面信息
That feeds a view of the road ahead to the system inside.
-什么系统
-What system?
-这儿有个引擎盖
-Well, there's a bonnet here.
来看看 准备好了吗
Come round, I'll show you the... the gubbins. Ready?
咳咳 这就是了
There it is.
啥 就是个人
Well, it's just a man!
-这儿只有个人
-It's just a man in there!
-并不是啊
-It isn't.
-就是
It is!
-不不不 不是
No. No.
他不只是个人
It's not just a man
他还是个罗马尼亚人
This is a Romanian man.
我在给祖国的新移民提供工作
I am providing employment for newcomers to our country.
-天啊
-Oh, God
-你这话我就不爱听了
-What do you mean, "Oh, God"?
想想看 谷歌 嗯
Think about it. Google, yes?
谷歌在让电子蚕食人们的饭碗
Google, they use electronics to take away the work of a man.
但这个给他工作 让他体面生活
This gives him a job, it gives him dignity.
-体面吗
-Dignity?
-真的 很体面
-Yes, dignity.
有点封建气息啊
It's a bit feudal, isn't it?
这明明是天才气息
It's a bit brilliant is what it is
我要关上引擎盖了
Let me close the bonnet.
我要开始处女航了
I'm gonna go for my first-ever drive.
首先上梯砸
I'll go to t'foot of our stairs here,
这是个约克郡俗语
which is a Yorkshire expression.
厉害的是 上下车十分容易
The great thing is, it's so easy to get in and out of, you know.
看到了没
Look, there I am.
现在可以不用手机 我可以用传声装置
-Now I don't need the phone I can use my speaking tube.
天啊 这下面可藏着一个人啊
-Oh, God!There's a man in there!
罗马尼亚语的后退是什么来着
What's Romanian for "backwards"?
?napoi 应该是这个
?napoi, I think.
没错 还能双语控制
?napoi. It is, obviously It's bilingual.
太魔性了
This is evil!
谷歌都没做到的 我做到了
Google hasn't made it work, I have.
倒 我还是说英语了
?na... Backwards I'll just stick to English.
倒 倒 倒
Backwards. Backwards.
十分感谢
Thank you so much.
女士们先生们 这就是英国工程
British engineering, ladies and gentlemen,
和罗马尼亚零部件
with Romanian parts.
美妙的结合
What a combination that is.
擦 我的头
Shit! Ah, my head!
行吧行吧
Yep. Whatever.
-我很高兴他走了
-Anyway, I'm glad he's gone
-我也是
-So am I.
我还十分开心的是接下来的内容
No, I'm particularly glad because of what's coming up next.
啊对对对 在之前的节目里
Oh, yes! Yes. Now, right at the beginning of this series,
杰里米在葡萄牙竞速中打赌
Jeremy Clarkson said, when we were at a race track in Portugal -
是在广大观众面前说哦
and he said it on the television -
如果他的迈凯伦P1
that if his McLaren P1 wasn't faster
比哈蒙德的保时捷918和我的法拉利拉法慢
than Hammond's Porsche 918 or my Ferrari The Ferrari,
我们可以拆掉他的房子
we could knock his house down.
正如你所见 他失败了
Well, it wasn't,
所以趁杰里米不在家的周末
so, one weekend when Jeremy was away,
我们 放影片吧
we...Well, roll the tape.
这就是了
This is it,
科茨沃尔德石材所建 200年历史的房子
200 years old and built from beautiful Cotswold stone.
我要说清楚
Now, I want to make it absolutely clear
这是杰里米的房子 如假包换
that this is Jeremy Clarkson's actual house.
没错 我以我孩子们的性命发誓
Yeah, it really is I'd swear to my children's lives on that.
这是杰里米的房子
It's Jeremy's house.
他爱这里的风景才买的
He bought it when he fell in love with the view.
这风景很漂亮
It is a lovely view, actually.
是的 现在我们可以除掉这碍眼的房子
It is. It'll be even better soon,
让这风景更上一层楼
without a house in it.
我们的计划很简单
Our plan was to smash the place down
用大家伙砸掉就行
with some big demolition equipment.
但是有个问题
But there was a problem.
在这个地方
In this country,
如果政府发现蝙蝠居住在此的话
you can't knock a house down
你就无法拆除房屋
if the council find evidence of bats living in it.
因为这里有蝙蝠
Well, they did,
所以我们被要求
and now we've been told
要先轻轻用手把屋顶掀了
we've got to take the roof off, quietly and by hand,
让蝙蝠有机会逃命
to give the bats the chance to go and live elsewhere.
詹姆斯 我发现现在只有我一个人在做这活
James, I can't help but notice I am doing all of the work here.
没办法 我不喜欢这工作
Yeah, you're gonna have to. I don't like it.
这就是个梯子 很简单只要爬上来就好啊
It's just a ladder! It's a simple enough thing to operate. Climb it!
你又不是我 一点都不简单
Not if you're me, it's not
这儿有多少蝙蝠
How many bats are there?
-一只
-One
-就一只
-One?
-是 就一只
-Yes, a bat
-就宰了它啊
-Just kill it.
那我们会进监狱的 没门
We'll go to prison, mate We can't.
就因为那长着翅膀的杂种老鼠
Just because that little winged-mouse bastard
倒挂在这 还一脸得意
is hanging upside down in there, feeling smug with himself
所以我得爬上梯子 没法拆迁?
cos I'm up this ladder, we can't knock the house down?
是的 上来吧
We've got to do it, no choice, so get up here and get on with it.
哈蒙德你知道我恐高
Hammond, I hate.. I hate heights You know I do.
我讨厌梯子 我恨蝙蝠
I hate ladders, I hate bats.
几小时后
Many hours later,
蜘蛛侠并没来帮忙
and with no help at all from Spider-Man,
终于掀开了屋顶 蝙蝠可以飞走了
the roof was finally off and the bat was free to move.
但它会吗
But would it?
它为什么不飞去那边呢
Why doesn't it go and live in there?
因为 讲道理啊 那对蝙蝠可是个好地方
Because, let's be honest, that's perfect if you're a bat.
是啊 可是它得乐意搬走啊
Yeah, well, it might, but it's got to decide to do so.
-能给它一点鼓励吗
-Can we encourage it?
-好吧 你可以在谷仓里
-Yes, James.Why don't you go and stand in that barn
发出挑逗的叫声来吸引吧
and squeak in a sultry and erotic manner?
那晚  蜘蛛侠侠站在谷仓里
That night, Spider-Man stood in the barn,
发出诱惑而挑逗的叫声
squeaking in a sultry and erotic manner...
蝙蝠也终于拜倒在了石榴裙下
...and the bat eventually succumbed.
第二天一早 我们终于可以拆迁了
So, the next morning, we were ready to go.
这东西很有用啊 真给力
This thing really works! This rocks!Oh, my word!
如此这般 很快就可以搞定了
At this rate, we'd be done and dusted in no time.
但是 我的挑剔同事又添乱了
However, my finickity colleague had an issue.
-哈蒙德
-Hammond!
-干嘛 -停下
-What?-Stop!
-啥 -停
你不能这样把它砸的粉碎
You don't just smash it to pieces.
应该分解它 让它齐整地倒下
You're supposed to dismantle it and leave it in neat piles.
务必要整齐地拆除 而不是砸碎
It's got to be tidied up You can't leave it like that.
要是这么做 会完成的更快
It's actually quicker if you do it methodically.
我去 只有你会说这种话
Oh, God Only you would say that!
整齐地拆除会更好 因为废墟更容易处理
You want neat piles of bits that can be carted away.You need to work on that bit
应该这样做 从那部分开始
and that bit to start with,
剩下的部分会齐整地倒成一堆
then the rest falls neatly into a heap.
你是如何让这活变得如此无聊的
How can you make even this boring?
这不无聊 只是教你经验 我是过来人
It's not boring. It's the way... I've watched it done.
该这么做 不是砸碎它 我来吧
That's how you do it You don't just smash it I'll do it.
詹姆斯抢走了我的机器
James then commandeered my machine...
但我带着新装备卷土重来
so I got another one and carried on regardless.
啊哈 抓到了
Ah! I've got it!
就像在玩夹娃娃机
Oh, it's like winning one of those things at the fair.
因为我 我们至少有进度可言
Thanks to me, at least,
progress was being made.
可是
However...
我好像卡住了
I'm stuck on something.
啊哦 我弄坏了我的挖掘机
Oh! Oh, I've broken
my digger. Oh, dear.
我倒下了 詹姆斯则一事无成
With me out of action
and James achieving nothing,
我们需要一个新办法
a new approach was needed.
但是首先 我们要清场
But first, we had to clear the site
清理杰里米的珍贵物品
of Jeremy's most treasured possessions.
夏奇拉
Shakira.
还是夏奇拉的
好刺眼!
Oh!
诅咒娃娃上有你的照片
That is a... strong image.
看 这儿有一本相册 可能很珍贵吧
It's a tiny doll with pins
in it, and your face.
-但是有一点恼人
Look, this is his photo album.
It's probably really precious.
-什么
-What?
-全都是我啊 -嗯哼
-They're all of me. -Yep.
至此 我们决定不清场了
At this point, we
decided not to clear the site
让杰里米的东西随风去吧
of his treasured possessions
直接启动B计划
and moved swiftly to plan B.
简单说两句?
Short ceremony,say a few words?
算了吧
Nah.
-这
- That...
-搞定了
That got it.
所以 直说吧
So, let's just get this straight.
你们炸掉了我房子里的
You blew up...
那张骑马的画作?
that picture of me on the horse?
-是的
-Yep.-Yep.
伴随着我的失落 是时候结束了 感谢收看
And on that terrible disappointment,
it's time to end. Thanks for watching.
下周见
See you next week.
晚安
Good night!